{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which is not a MOSFET terminal?", "opta": "Gate", "optb": "Drain", "optc": "Source", "optd": "Base", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For a CMOS gate, which is the best speed-power product?", "opta": "1.4 pJ", "optb": "1.6 pJ", "optc": "2.4 pJ", "optd": "3.3 pJ", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which transistor element is used in CMOS logic?", "opta": "FET", "optb": "MOSFET", "optc": "Bipolar", "optd": "Unijunction", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a TTL circuit, if an excessive number of load gate inputs are connected, ________.", "opta": "VOH(min) drops below VOH", "optb": "VOH drops below VOH(min)", "optc": "VOH exceeds VOH(min)", "optd": "VOH and VOH(min) are unaffected", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The greater the propagation delay, the ________.", "opta": "lower the maximum frequency", "optb": "higher the maximum frequency", "optc": "maximum frequency is unaffected", "optd": "minimum frequency is unaffected", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An open-drain gate is the CMOS counterpart of ________.", "opta": "an open-collector TTL gate", "optb": "a tristate TTL gate", "optc": "a bipolar junction transistor", "optd": "an emitter-coupled logic gate", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A TTL NAND gate with IIL(max) of \u20131.6 mA per input drives eight TTL inputs. How much current does the drive output sink?", "opta": "\u201312.8 mA", "optb": "\u20138 mA", "optc": "\u20131.6 mA", "optd": "\u201325.6 mA", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The nominal value of the dc supply voltage for TTL and CMOS is ________.", "opta": "+3 V", "optb": "+5 V", "optc": "+9 V", "optd": "+12 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which logic family combines the advantages of CMOS and TTL?", "opta": "BiCMOS", "optb": "TTL/CMOS", "optc": "ECL", "optd": "TTL/MOS", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which equation is correct?", "opta": "VNL = VIL(max) + VOL(max)", "optb": "VNH = VOH(min) + VIH(min)", "optc": "VNL = VOH(min) \u2013 VIH(min)", "optd": "VNH = VOH(min) \u2013 VIH(min)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The active switching element used in all TTL circuits is the ________.", "opta": "bipolar junction transistor (BJT)", "optb": "field-effect transistor (FET)", "optc": "metal-oxide semiconductor field-effect transistor (MOSFET)", "optd": "unijunction transistor (UJ)", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An open-collector output requires ________.", "opta": "a pull-down resistor", "optb": "a pull-up resistor", "optc": "no output resistor", "optd": "an output resistor", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Most TTL logic used today is some form of ________.", "opta": "Schottky TTL", "optb": "tristate TTL", "optc": "low-power TTL", "optd": "open-collector TTL", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A standard TTL circuit with a totem-pole output can sink, in the LOW state (IOL(max)), ________.", "opta": "16 mA", "optb": "20 mA", "optc": "16 A", "optd": "20 A", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One output structure of a TTL gate is often referred to as a ________.", "opta": "totem-pole arrangement", "optb": "diode arrangement", "optc": "JBT arrangement", "optd": "base, emitter, collector arrangement", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "It is best not to leave unused TTL inputs unconnected (open) because of TTL's ________.", "opta": "noise sensitivity", "optb": "low-current requirement", "optc": "open-collector outputs", "optd": "tristate construction", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not an output state for tristate logic?", "opta": "HIGH", "optb": "LOW", "optc": "High-Z", "optd": "Low-Z", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "TTL is alive and well, particularly in ________.", "opta": "industrial applications", "optb": "educational applications", "optc": "military applications", "optd": "commercial applications", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A TTL NAND gate with IIH(max) of 40 A per input drives ten TTL inputs. How much current does the drive output source?", "opta": "40 A", "optb": "200 A", "optc": "400 A", "optd": "800 A", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A certain gate draws 1.8 A when its output is HIGH and 3.3 \u00b5A when its output is LOW. VCC is 5 V and the gate is operated on a 50% duty cycle. What is the average power dissipation (PD)?", "opta": "2.55 W", "optb": "1.27 W", "optc": "12.75 W", "optd": "5 W", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "PMOS and NMOS circuits are used largely in ________.", "opta": "MSI functions", "optb": "LSI functions", "optc": "diode functions", "optd": "TTL functions", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If ICCH is specified as 1.1 mA when VCC is 5 V and if the gate is in a static (noncharging) HIGH output state, the power dissipation (PD) of the gate is ________.", "opta": "5.5 mW", "optb": "5.5 W", "optc": "5 mW", "optd": "1.1 mW", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not a precaution for handling CMOS?", "opta": "Devices should be placed with pins down on a grounded surface, such as a metal plate.", "optb": "All tools, test equipment, and metal workbenches should be earth grounded.", "optc": "CMOS devices should not be inserted into sockets or PC boards with the power on.", "optd": "Wear wool clothes at all times.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which factor does not affect CMOS loading?", "opta": "Charging time associated with the output resistance of the driving gate", "optb": "Discharging time associated with the output resistance of the driving gate", "optc": "Output capacitance of the load gates", "optd": "Input capacitance of the load gates", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not part of emitter-coupled logic (ECL)?", "opta": "Differential amplifier", "optb": "Bias circuit", "optc": "Emitter-follower circuit", "optd": "Totem-pole circuit", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}